[
    {
        "answer": "Marvel Comics",
        "question": "Who publishes the Fantastic Four comics?",
        "sentence": "\nThe Fantastic Four is a fictional superhero team appearing in American comic books published by Marvel Comics ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Fantastic Four",
        "question": "What is the name of the fictional superhero team that appears in comic books?",
        "sentence": "\nThe Fantastic Four is a fictional superhero team appearing in American comic books published by Marvel Comics ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Nov. 1961",
        "question": "When did the Fantastic Four debut?",
        "sentence": "The team debuted in The Fantastic Four # 1 ( cover dated Nov. 1961 ) , helping usher in a new level of realism in the medium ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Fantastic Four",
        "question": "What was the title of the first issue of American Idol?",
        "sentence": "The team debuted in The Fantastic Four # 1 ( cover dated Nov. 1961 ) , helping usher in a new level of realism in the medium ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Stan Lee",
        "question": "Along with Jack Kirby, who created the first superhero team?",
        "sentence": "It was the first superhero team created by artist / co - plotter Jack Kirby and editor / co - plotter Stan Lee , who developed a collaborative approach to creating comics with this title ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Jack Kirby",
        "question": "Who created the first superhero team?",
        "sentence": "It was the first superhero team created by artist / co - plotter Jack Kirby and editor / co - plotter Stan Lee , who developed a collaborative approach to creating comics with this title ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Mister Fantastic",
        "question": "Who is the leader of the Fantastic Four?",
        "sentence": "The four characters traditionally associated with the Fantastic Four , who gained superpowers after exposure to cosmic rays during a scientific mission to outer space , are : Mister Fantastic ( Reed Richards ) , a scientific genius and the leader of the group , who can stretch his body into incredible lengths and shapes ; the Invisible Woman ( Susan \" Sue \" Storm ) , who eventually married Reed , who can render herself invisible and project powerful invisible force fields and blasts ; the Human Torch ( Johnny Storm ) , Sue 's younger brother , who can generate flames , surround himself with them and fly ; the monstrous Thing ( Ben Grimm ) , their grumpy but benevolent friend , a former college football star , Reed 's college roommate and a good pilot , who possesses tremendous superhuman strength , durability and endurance due to his stone - like flesh ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "1961",
        "question": "When did the Fantastic Four first appear?",
        "sentence": "Since the 1961 introduction , the Fantastic Four has been portrayed as a somewhat dysfunctional , yet loving , family ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "celebrity status",
        "question": "Instead of anonymity or secret identities, what did comic archetype members prefer?",
        "sentence": "Breaking convention with other comic archetypes , the members squabbled , held grudges both deep and petty , and eschewed anonymity or secret identities in favor of celebrity status ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "the Kree Empire",
        "question": "Ronan the Accuser is a member of what empire?",
        "sentence": "They are also well known for their recurring encounters with characters such as the villainous monarch Doctor Doom ; the planet - devouring Galactus ; the Kree Empire 's ruthless and tyrannical enforcer Ronan the Accuser ; Annihilus , ruler of the Negative Zone ; the sea - dwelling prince Namor ; the spacefaring Silver Surfer ; and the Skrull warrior Kl'rt ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "the planet",
        "question": "What planet is Galactus on?",
        "sentence": "They are also well known for their recurring encounters with characters such as the villainous monarch Doctor Doom ; the planet - devouring Galactus ; the Kree Empire 's ruthless and tyrannical enforcer Ronan the Accuser ; Annihilus , ruler of the Negative Zone ; the sea - dwelling prince Namor ; the spacefaring Silver Surfer ; and the Skrull warrior Kl'rt ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "four",
        "question": "How many animated series has The Fantastic Four been adapted into?",
        "sentence": "The Fantastic Four have been adapted into other media , including four animated series and four live - action films ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "four",
        "question": "How many animated series has The Fantastic Four been adapted into?",
        "sentence": "The Fantastic Four have been adapted into other media , including four animated series and four live - action films ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Jack Kirby",
        "question": "Who was working for Marvel in 1968?",
        "sentence": ": \u200a 17 \u200a Lee provided one of his earliest recorded comments on the creation of the Fantastic Four for a fanzine in 1968 , during which time Jack Kirby was also working at Marvel ( Kirby himself is interviewed separately in the same publication ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "1968",
        "question": "In what year did Lee provide one of his earliest recorded comments on the creation of the Fantastic Four for a fanzine?",
        "sentence": ": \u200a 17 \u200a Lee provided one of his earliest recorded comments on the creation of the Fantastic Four for a fanzine in 1968 , during which time Jack Kirby was also working at Marvel ( Kirby himself is interviewed separately in the same publication ) ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Jack",
        "question": "Who created the characters visually?",
        "sentence": "When asked who conceived the team , him or Kirby , Lee responded \" Both \u2013 ' twas mainly my idea , but Jack created characters visually \" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Kirby",
        "question": "Who did Lee say conceived the team?",
        "sentence": "When asked who conceived the team , him or Kirby , Lee responded \" Both \u2013 ' twas mainly my idea , but Jack created characters visually \" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Kirby and Publisher Martin Goodman",
        "question": "Who did Lee mention in preparation of his synopsis?",
        "sentence": "Lee noted the involvement of both Kirby and Publisher Martin Goodman prior to preparing his synopsis : \" After kicking it around with Martin and Jack for a while I decided to call our quaint quartet the Fantastic Four ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Fantastic Four",
        "question": "What did Lee call his quartet after kicking it around with Martin and Jack for a while?",
        "sentence": "Lee noted the involvement of both Kirby and Publisher Martin Goodman prior to preparing his synopsis : \" After kicking it around with Martin and Jack for a while I decided to call our quaint quartet the Fantastic Four ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Jack",
        "question": "Who did I write a synopsis for?",
        "sentence": "I wrote a detailed first synopsis for Jack to follow and the rest is history . \""
    },
    {
        "answer": "1970",
        "question": "In what year did Lee confirm his involvement in the Fantastic Four?",
        "sentence": "In a 1970 Fanzine interview he confirmed Lee 's involvement in the creation of the Fantastic Four but took credit for the main characters and ideas , stating \" It was my idea ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Kirby",
        "question": "Who claims he came up with the idea for the Fantastic Four?",
        "sentence": "Kirby claims he came up with the idea for the Fantastic Four in Marvel 's offices , and that Lee merely added the dialogue after the story was pencilled ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "the Baxter Building Headquarters",
        "question": "Along with civilian garb, what building was introduced in the third issue of the Fantastic Four?",
        "sentence": ": \u200a 4 \u200a  It is important to note , however , that the Fantastic Four originally wore civilian garb instead of uniforms , which were only introduced ( along with the Baxter Building Headquarters ) in the third issue of the series following readership feedback ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "civilian garb",
        "question": "What did the Fantastic Four originally wear instead of uniforms?",
        "sentence": ": \u200a 4 \u200a  It is important to note , however , that the Fantastic Four originally wore civilian garb instead of uniforms , which were only introduced ( along with the Baxter Building Headquarters ) in the third issue of the series following readership feedback ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "A typed synopsis by Lee",
        "question": "What exists for the introductory segment of the first Fantastic Four issue?",
        "sentence": "A typed synopsis by Lee for the introductory segment of the first Fantastic Four issue exists and outlines the characters and their origins , with various minor differences to the published version ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Earl Wells",
        "question": "Who wrote in The Comics Journal that his existence does not assert its place in the creation?",
        "sentence": "However Earl Wells , writing in The Comics Journal , points out that its existence does not assert its place in the creation : \" [ W]e have no way of knowing of whether Lee wrote the synopsis after a discussion with Kirby in which Kirby supplied most of the ideas \" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "78",
        "question": "How many Fantastic Four members are there?",
        "sentence": ": \u200a 78 \u200a It is also notable that the Fantastic Four 's first adventure in 1961 depicts a team of four adventurers ( three men and a woman ) led by a Professor travelling to the Earth \u2019s centre and encountering giant monsters while contending with a human protagonist who is also from the surface world ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "a Professor",
        "question": "Who is the leader of the Fantastic Four?",
        "sentence": ": \u200a 78 \u200a It is also notable that the Fantastic Four 's first adventure in 1961 depicts a team of four adventurers ( three men and a woman ) led by a Professor travelling to the Earth \u2019s centre and encountering giant monsters while contending with a human protagonist who is also from the surface world ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Lee",
        "question": "R.C. Harvey believes that the Fantastic Four was more likely to have been created by Kirby than who?",
        "sentence": "Comics historian R. C. Harvey believes the Fantastic Four was a continuation of the work Kirby previously did , and so \" more likely Kirby 's creations than Lee 's \" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "R. C. Harvey",
        "question": "Who believes the Fantastic Four was a continuation of Kirby's work?",
        "sentence": "Comics historian R. C. Harvey believes the Fantastic Four was a continuation of the work Kirby previously did , and so \" more likely Kirby 's creations than Lee 's \" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "69 Wells",
        "question": "Who argues that Lee's contributions set the framework within which Kirby worked?",
        "sentence": ": \u200a 69 \u200a  Wells argues that Lee 's contributions set the framework within which Kirby worked , and this made Lee \" more responsible \" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Kirby",
        "question": "Wells argues that Lee's contributions set the framework within which who worked?",
        "sentence": ": \u200a 69 \u200a  Wells argues that Lee 's contributions set the framework within which Kirby worked , and this made Lee \" more responsible \" ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "Nov. 1961",
        "question": "When was The Fantastic Four # 1 released?",
        "sentence": ": \u200a 122 \u200a  The release of The Fantastic Four # 1 ( Nov. 1961 ) was an unexpected success ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "122",
        "question": "How many copies of The Fantastic Four were released?",
        "sentence": ": \u200a 122 \u200a  The release of The Fantastic Four # 1 ( Nov. 1961 ) was an unexpected success ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "issue # 3",
        "question": "What issue number did Lee start printing the letters in a letter column with?",
        "sentence": "The title began to receive fan mail and Lee started printing the letters in a letter column with issue # 3 ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "fan mail",
        "question": "What kind of mail did the title begin to receive?",
        "sentence": "The title began to receive fan mail and Lee started printing the letters in a letter column with issue # 3 ."
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Greatest Comic Magazine in the World",
        "question": "What was the slogan of the third issue?",
        "sentence": "Also with the third issue , Lee created the hyperbolic slogan \" The Greatest Comic Magazine in the World !"
    },
    {
        "answer": "The Greatest Comic Magazine in the World",
        "question": "What was the slogan of the third issue?",
        "sentence": "Also with the third issue , Lee created the hyperbolic slogan \" The Greatest Comic Magazine in the World !"
    }
]